In the texts and the accompanying book,
you will observe frequent occurrences of a sequence of two identical consonant letters.
It is important to remember that this indicates that the consonant sound in question is noticeably longer than for a single letter.
Listen to and practice this distinction in the pairs of words that are now to be spoken.
The first in each pair has a short consonant in the middle, the second a long consonant.
Here is the first pair.
Money.
paṇam (பணம்)
Make.
paṇṇu (பண்ணு)
Now the second pair. Mind.
manam (மனம்)
Cheek.
kannam (கன்னம்)
And another pair. Yes.
aamaa (ஆமா)
Mother.
ammaa (அம்மா)
And another. Art.
kale (கலை)
Stone.
kallu (கல்லு)
And another. Tamarind.
puḷi (புளி)
Dot.
puḷḷi (புள்ளி)
And another, to come.
vara (வர)
She is coming.
varraa (வர்றா)
And now the last pair. Usefulness.
payan (பயன்)
Boy.
payyan (பையன்)